The Story So Far
Countless new residents have arrived
in the Great Tree Village.
Such as the enormous minotaurs.
The half-horse, half-humanoid centaurs.
The nyunyu daphne wood spirits.
In order to welcome our 200 new residents,
we invited representatives from
each race to discuss how to proceed.
Allow me to apologize for not having
suitable homes ready for you.
I'd hoped to ask for your help
in getting your peoples settled here...
You really don't need to be that deferent.
Nonsense! In your presence,
I am little more than a flake of dust
fallen in the corner of this room.
House dust, huh?
Let's all just relax and-
A cue card?
I choose to allow it this time.
Act more self-important.
You'd best be grateful.
Now lift up your head, Gruwald Raby Coll.
I have high hopes for
the work you will perform.
Excellent performance, Mayor!
Sir! It is my pleasure to serve!
Thanks.
We all now live together, so let us
put aside formalities and take it easy.
I have assigned each of your people
a representative who will look after you.
Narf will attend to the minotaurs.
Lattiaci to the centaurs.
It is my pleasure.
And for the nyunyu daphne...
Beastwoman
Mamu
Mamu! At your service.
We are glad to have you.
I will do all that I can!
Mamu moved here from Howling Village
along with Sena and the others.
Mamu can handle it!
I tasked her with this after Sena
recommended her for a higher-level position.
Now, as for where
each of your people will live...
The village we had built was
meant for human-sized beings.
So instead, we decided to build separate
villages fit for the minotaurs and centaurs.
The thought was that
letting them live separately
would make it easier to live
and work with their people.
We used the locations
Lea and the others found.
Location 2
Location 3
Planned Route
Building roads and
irrigation channels to them.
There's a lot of forest to clear,
so I could use your help.
Okay!
All right.
Ready?
Go!
Roar!
How much should we burn?
No burning, please!
Again, I want to build a road
in this direction.
Okay!
Hup!
How was that?
It's the right direction, at least.
Hrmph.
I see room for improvement, Lasty.
I haven't gone all out yet!
Settle down now!
Forest of Death
We could lose the entire forest at this rate.
Death
Let's relax, okay? Take it easy. Gently!
I had them refrain from using their
full power as we progressed.
What are you dancing for?
We should continue
alongside the river for now.
These too, if you would!
Dig! Dig! Dig!
Pat! Pat! Pat!
Drop! Drop! Drop!
Dash!
Chop!
This is such a slog. Can't we burn them?
No.
Meanwhile
I beg your pardon.
These are for young Alfred.
The latest from Zabuton.
They do seem a bit large, however.
Hasty as ever.
In the second village, we are
constructing houses for the minotaurs.
They're quite tall, so we're building
taller one-story homes.
Yes, not only are the buildings tall,
but the furniture is large too.
This is not a table, but a chair.
That there is the table.
I feel almost like a child again.
These are beds?
They're certainly unique.
Yes.
Built so our horns don't hit them.
Minotaur-style Bed
Zzzzz...
Here in our third village,
we have homes for the centaurs.
As their bodies are built like horses,
homes built like stables
apparently suit them best.
What a wide entrance.
Will you be adding doors?
Yes, but my kind have trouble
with ordinary doors.
So we plan to add a curtain
drawn by rope instead.
Makes sense.
They have sliding doors
for rainy days too, apparently.
Oh, why are you in such a bad mood?
Allow me.
Let us begin.
Peak a boo.
What did you just do? Show me!
It's a secret.
A month went by,
and everyone's hard work
brought both villages to shape.
The distance is about this far,
measured in steps.
So the third village stands here...
It's a good thing they're
finished before winter.
For sure.
We couldn't leave them
out in the winter cold.
So...
What will these villages be named?
Good question.
Based on location, they could be,
Upton, Middleton, and Downton...
Upton
Middleton
Downton
But those don't really sound right...
Maybe just Village One,
Village Two, and Village Three.
Village One
Village Two
Village Three
These will be temporary,
so if anyone has better ideas-
Let's avoid any changes, shall we?
Surely you see how hard it is to rewrite
every document we've made?
Right...
We can leave Village One
unassigned for now,
but Gordon should be mayor of Village Two.
And Gruwald mayor of Village Three, yes?
I guess so.
But if we name them
all mayors like our own...
Yes, it might be best to create
a clearer hierarchy with your title.
Like High Mayor.
High Mayor
Or Great Mayor.
Great Mayor
Or King Mayor.
King Mayor
Let's not go that far.
If I may...
When will a village be built for my people?
Ah, sorry.
We decided against building
a nyunyu daphne village.
Is that so...?
Then our dream of finding
a home to set our roots
remains no more than just that.
Pining Cone
Hang on now!
I have a favor to ask of your people
in each of our villages.
Since the nyunyu daphne
are more suited to staying put,
our plan was to place them
at important locations
and task them with standing watch
and relaying information.
Their kind are able to communicate
through what seems like telepathy.
Peaceful.
They made perfect messengers.
Mild.
Mild?
Why not ask that they watch over
the uninhabited Village One as well?
Good thinking!
Very well!
It would be unbearable to have it
waste away after all the work put into it.
We also had them act as lighting
in the evenings.
Now that each race has
settled into their homes,
I'd like to assign jobs to the residents
of villages One and Two, but...
Hrngh...
Stupefied
Mayor...
We have a bit of a problem.
As do we.
What sort?
Apparently, the minotaurs and centaurs
weren't suited to hunting in the forest.
Typical Target
They look plenty strong to me.
The minotaurs are a tranquil people.
Some of them are capable in battle,
but that does not leave them fit for hunting.
Most of the centaurs are refugees
hardly able to fend for themselves.
I never realized hunting was so difficult
because the inferno wolves
handled it for us.
Those wolves have unimaginable strength.
We should keep the people out of the woods
and place more defenders in both villages.
Good thinking.
Reliable Defenses
Let's talk with Kuro and Zabuton.
You got it
Do the nyunyu daphne need guards?
They seem good enough at avoiding combat.
Well, actually, you know...
We can do it!
It seems they're quite strong.
But they mostly fight via ambush,
so they can't hunt large numbers.
Mobility Problems
How do they even fight?
We decided to leave hunting
to Kuro and the rest.
And we set about
tilling fields in each village.
The idea was to make them self-sufficient,
even without hunting. But...
Nothing seems to be taking root.
Why not?
Do you always plant
these seeds in this season?
The seeds? Uhh...
When did we plant them again?
Dunno.
Umm...
There was a reason we were unsure,
despite raising crops all these years.
The only reason I was able to raise crops
and live in the middle of the forest
was because I had the power of
the almighty farming tool.
Its divine powers made soil fertile,
let me plant any seed I imagined,
and made the crops grow faster.
Our ability to harvest
despite the season or weather
is the main reason we were
able to grow to such a size.
Unfortunately, I am the
only one able to use it.
It is all I can do to prepare our own fields.
They're just too big!
Home grown and raised.
So the new villages are to handle their fields
without the use of the almighty farming tool.
This is harder than I thought.
We'll have to keep trying.
In that case...
By laying down straw to keep the soil
from getting cold, we may have more luck.
With winter on approach,
it might be best to plant wheat.
You know your stuff.
Hardly.
I merely helped with farm work
on occasion in my last village.
You have experience, then!
We continued preparing the fields
with guidance from our farming senpai.
The wheat we plant now
will sit through the winter
and be ready for harvest before summer.
Half a year's wait, huh?
I guess that's the norm.
We've grown too accustomed to
the Great Tree Village's fields.
Seems like.
It's probably not normal for pineapples
to grow in such snowy climates.
All the more reason to be grateful
to the god of agriculture!
What might these be?
Statues of the gods of creation
and agriculture.
I was thinking of building a shrine
and housing them there.
Oh, please do.
These are fantastic sculptures.
The one with the stick is the God of Creation,
but who is the other?
The God of Agriculture, apparently.
That's an interesting take on them.
Guess different lands have
different interpretations.
They made me
an old man again!
Farming Life in Another World 2!
While the minotaurs handled agriculture...
Keep up!
Yes, ma'am!
...the centaurs used their abilities
to develop a new line of work.
Centaur Delivery
Their Centaur Delivery service began
shipping goods between villages.
They were unfit for hunting,
but more than able to outrun
any monsters.
Centaur Delivery
Great Tree Village
Village Two
Village Three
The adult centaurs were each tasked
with regular deliveries.
New route record!
Oww...
Perhaps that was too fast.
I just hope they put safety first.
Mayor, a moment, if I may.
What is it?
I noticed you have a horse on your farm here.
We do, yeah.
My Recommendations!!
Horse
Baaaah~
Goat
Chicken
Our merchant friend brought us one
along with goats and chickens.
I've always wanted to ride a horse, you know.
Unfortunately...
Hey!
Look! I've got a carrot!
...it doesn't listen to a word I say.
If you can communicate with horses,
can you ask it to give me a ride?
I'm sorry, I do not speak horse.
However, if that horse is not
your trusty steed...
Hup!
Okay. All set.
Let us begin.
Wow, we're up so high!
Grab hold of my shoulders if you wish.
Please hold on tight.
Whoa! What a bumpy ride.
We'll now pick up the pace.
Sorry.
Not at all.
How does it feel taking your first ride?
It's great!
Some other day
Hmm?
What's with you all of a sudden?
You know how to let someone ride now, is it?
Okay, giddy up!
Good! Keep that up.
How can this be?!
Good work.
There, there.
What?!
In a good mood, huh?
How dare you...
Good morning, Mayor!
Lovely day, isn't it?
What's going on here?
You are headed off, yes?
Please, ride on me!
It's too dangerous to ride
this strange, wild beast!
That's my horse, though.
See? It's dangerous!
It's not even wild.
Let's settle down and be friends, okay?
Friends!
What are you dancing for?
I will hold you to your word.
I didn't want them
waiting for me every morning,
so I promised to ride each every other day.
So, umm!
Is there anything I can do for you?
Anything you need?
Or don't understand?
You can ask for anything!
The sky.
Yes?!
Is blue.
Yes! What lovely weather!
The roots of the crops grow deeper
than imagined, so it's best to till deep.
Understood, Gordon-senpai!
All seems to be well.
Yup.
At first, I was worried about
the huge influx all at once.
How are you feeling?
Well enough, thank you.
I hope each village can
eventually support itself.
For now, they all rely on you.
It's nice to be useful.
But I'd like them to be able to
resolve some things on their own.
Relying too much on the convenience
of the almighty farming tool
would leave me worried for the future.
I'm healthy and well
thanks to divine powers, but...
Never know when a cold
might knock me out, right?
We can deal with that when it happens.
Worry all you want, you won't be
retiring carefree soon anyway.
So perhaps you ought just relax.
You think?
I do!
I guess so.
What's wrong?
Oh, I can smell the answer.
You handed him over on purpose, didn't you?
Best get that diaper changed!
While reflecting an unusual amount
on my own future,
I remembered another
important problem we faced.
The Great Tree Village is filled with women.
Beyond filled. Overflowing!
By comparison,
there are hardly any men.
Men
Women
This has me worried
about our future.
I've asked for new male inhabitants,
but have had no luck.
But now we have a great
number of newcomers!
This should solve those worries!
Men?
Of our 72, 28 are male.
Is that right?
Do we need soldiers?
Are we to be sent off to battle?
Nope! Nothing like that.
So it's like this, see?
Explaining
Which means that and that!
I see...
It is custom for us minotaurs
to marry other minotaurs.
Due to our size, if nothing else.
Hadn't thought of that.
For better or worse, the minotaurs were
to be left to marry among their own.
Which left the centaurs.
It felt wrong to bring
this question to the women,
...but it had to be done
for the sake of our future!
Our men?
Thirty of our own are male,
but all are but boys.
The adults are off at war.
I see...
So you have boys, if not men yet.
This might be hard to answer,
but I must stress that it is important.
It's in regards to centaur marriages.
I am single!
That's fine and all, but...
Do centaurs ever marry other races?
Not ordinarily.
This is a difficult hurdle, I guess.
It may prove difficult for centaurs
to pair with other races.
However, if you demand one of our women
as price for our home here...
No, it's not like that.
I ask that you take me!
I am prepared to serve!
What?!
Relax, I'm not asking for anything like that.
Why not?
Why what?!
Do men not enjoy overpowering strong women?
Who told you that?
Just relax, okay? Relax...
Relax. Take it easy...
What are you dancing for?
I hope the centaurs also do
well enough among themselves.
Would you prefer I were more contemptuous?!
That's not what this is about!
Next time
Episode 3
Winter